Hello, Moonbase! Can you hear me?
哈罗, 月球基地! 你们能听到吗？
Yes!
能！
Yes, I can hear you loud and clear!
能, 你的声音很清楚很响亮！
What part of Earth are you speaking from?
你是在地球上哪个位置说话？
(DOCTOR) We're not on the Earth.
We're in a rocket orbiting the moon.
我们不在地球上, 我们在一架火箭上, 目前正在月球轨道
A rocket? But that's impossible!
火箭？这不可能啊！
I can assure you it's not impossible!
What is your emergency?
我可以向你保证这不是不可能！你的紧急状况是什么？
What's happening on Moonbase?
月球基地发生了什么事情？
We've been invaded! Aliens have taken over!
我们被入侵了！外星人占领了这里！
Put that cover back on.
把那个盖子放回去
T-Mat back to Earth and report to Commander Radnor.
传送回地球, 向指挥官 Radnor 汇报
(RASPING WHISPER)
Stop!
停下！
You will remain here!
你得待在这里！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Doctor, these aliens he described...
博士, 他说描述的外星人...
- Yes, Ice Warriors!
- What?
- 是了, 寒冰勇士！  - 什么？
Jamie and I have met them before.
They come from the planet Mars.
Jamie 和我之前跟他们遭遇过．他们来自火星
- What do they want?
- Mars is a dying planet.
- 他们想要什么？  - 火星是个要死的星球了
- I imagine that they want a new home.
- Why the moon?
- 我估计他们是想要一个新家  - 为什么选月球？
- I think it's just a stepping stone.
- What did you say? They're...Ice Warriors?
- 我想这只是一个垫脚石  - 你说他们叫什么来着, 是叫...寒冰勇士？
Yes, you know, Mars is a cold planet
and they've adapted to that.
是的, 你看, 火星是个寒冷的星球, 他们已经习惯了
It's heat they can't stand.
所以他们忍受不了炎热
We should just about be coming into range now.
我们现在应该快到地方了
Hello, Moonbase.
你好, 月球基地
(RASPING WHISPER) You will remain here!
你得待在这里！
That's the lot. The whole system's
completely operational again.
fixme 整个系统已经完全恢复可用了
We can now send to any city in the world?/?fixme
我们现在可以传送物品给世界上任何一个城市了？
- Yes, anywhere with a T-Mat centre.
- 是的, 只要这个城市有 T-Mat 中心
- Fewsham, Do you realise what you're doing?!
- I'm trying to save our lives!
- Fewsham, 你知道你在干什么吗？！  - 我尽力在救我们的命！
- Then what about the lives of the people on Earth?
- We're in no position to argue!
- 那地球上那么多人的命怎么办？  - 我们现在没资格讨价还价！
Why do you want control of T-Mat?
你们为什么想要控制 T-Mat？
If you're going to invade the Earth,
如果你们想要入侵地球
you'll be fighting the armed forces
of the entire world. You'll never succeed.
会有整个世界的武装力量跟你们斗争, 你们不会成功的
- There'll be too much resistance.
- There will be no resistance!
- 会有太多的反抗  - 不会有任何反抗！
What about us? What will happen to us?
我们怎么办？我们会怎么样？
You will remain alive as long as you are useful.
你们的命会留着, 只要你们还有用
You'll never get any help from me.
你们永远别想从我这里得到帮助
When the time comes, you will do
exactly what you are told...
等时间到了, 你会按我们说的照做的
..or die!
..不然就死！
Hello?
哈罗？
- Who are you?
- Oh!
- 你是谁？  - 噢！
- Mr Phipps, I presume?
- Yes, but where did you come from?
- Phipps 先生, 我估计？  - 是的, 不过你们从哪儿来的啊
From the rocket. We were talking on the radio.
从火箭啊, 我们在无线电里说过了
- Thank heavens you've made it. Are the others here too?
- Yeah, They're still in the rocket.
- 感谢上天你们成功了．还有其他人吗？  - 有, 他们还在火箭里面
- How many Ice Warriors are there?
- Those creatures you mean?
- 这里有多少寒冰勇士？  - 你是说那些怪物吗？
- Not many, but they're deadly.
- They have their weak points.
- 不多, 不过他们很厉害  - 他们有他们的弱点
Look, they've killed everybody here,
except Fewsham, who's helping them.
看, 他们已经杀了这里所有的人, 除了 Fewsham, 他在帮助他们
I see. Well, there's only one thing for it.
我明白了．这么说, 就只有一件事可干
- We shall have to destroy T-Mat.
- 我们必须得破坏 T-Mat
You will shortly dispatch a cargo
to certain cities on Earth.
很快你要发送一个货物到地球上的某个城市
Cargo? What sort of cargo?
货物？什么样的货物？
That's an Ice Warrior's. It's got Miss Kelly, but how...?
那就是寒冰勇士的fixme, 他们抓了 Kelly 小姐, 但怎么...？
Run!
跑！
Oh!
噢！
Stop!
停下！
(RASPING WHISPER) You must be destroyed!
必须消灭你！
You've got no orders to kill me!
你没有得到要杀死我的命令！
Your leader will want to speak to me!
你的头领想要同我谈谈的！
Humans are our enemies!
人类都是我们的敌人！
But I can be useful to you, like Fewsham!
但我对你们是有用的, 就像 Fewsham！
Your leader will be angry with you
if you kill me! I'm a genius!
如果你杀了我, 你的头领会发怒的！我是个天才！
(RASPING WHISPER) Genius!
天才！
You will come with me!
你跟我来！
The prisoner Kelly has escaped.
俘虏 Kelly 逃走了
This human was in the corridors.
这个人在走廊里
Who are you? Where are you from?
你是谁？你从哪里来？
I might ask you the same question!
我正想问你同样的问题！
You will find the human Kelly
and bring her back here!
如果你找到 Kelly 那个人类, 把她带回来！
- Who is this man?
- He's not one of the crew.
- 这个人是谁？  - 他不是我们组员之一
I don't know this man.
He must have just arrived here.
我不认识这个人, 他肯定是刚刚到这里的
Impossible - we control T-Mat.
How did you get here?
不可能 - 我们控制了 T-Mat．你怎么到这里的？
Our resources are not limited
to T-Mat, you know!
我们的资源可不止是 T-Mat, 你知道不？
- You arrived by other means? By space craft?
- Rockets haven't been used for years.
- 你用其它方法到这里的？坐宇宙飞船？  - 已经很多年不用火箭了
Then you are lying!
那你在撒谎！
You have been concealed here all the time.
你一直都躲在这里某个地方
(DOCTOR) But you can't be sure of that, can you, hmm?
但你还是没把握, 对不, 嗯？
The people of the Earth
地球上的人
may be preparing a whole fleet
of rockets to defend themselves with!
正在准备一整只火箭大军, 要保卫他们自己！
(ICE WARRIOR) No, Earth relies entirely on T-Mat.
不, 地球完全依赖于 T-Mat
There is no defence against our plans.
没有任何防御可以抵抗我们的计划
And what are your plans? Invasion by T-Mat?
你们的计划是什么？用 T-Mat 入侵？
There are too few of you to conquer
all the people of the Earth.
但你们人太少了, 没法征服地球上这么多人
(ICE WARRIOR) The Grand Marshall
has ordered the seeds to be prepared!
大元帅已经下令, 准备好种子
- You are to receive your instructions.
- Then guard the humans.
- 你要去接收指示  - 看好这些人类
If they try to escape, kill them!
如果他们打算逃跑, 杀了他们！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Why are you helping them?
你为什么要帮他们？
I've seen what they can do!
我见过了他们的能耐！
Do you know what is in that container?
你知道那容器里面是什么吗？
All I know is they want me to send
something to Earth by T-Mat.
我只是知道他们想要我用 T-Mat 传送什么东西到地球上去
- I suppose that's what's in it.
- I shall have to look inside,
- 我觉得就是那里面的东西  - 我打算去看一眼
and you are going to help me!
而你要帮我！
The Doctor's been captured? But couldn't you help him?
博士被抓住了？你们不能帮他吗？
I'm sorry, but there was nothing we could do.
抱歉, 但当时我们也没辙
- We had a job to reach here ourselves.
- Aye. So did we!
- fixme  - 嗯, 我们是！
Are you sure the Ice Warriors don't know about this place?
你确定寒冰勇士不知道这个地方？
One of them did find it, but I fixed up some kind
of a booby trap to the solar energy power line.
其中一个还真发现了, 但我用太阳能电源fixme
It looks those things are invulnerable!
看起来他们是刀枪不入的！
- No, the Doctor said they can't stand heat.
- That's right!
- 不, 博士说他们忍受不了热  - 对！
The heating system of the entire base
is controlled from the Centre.
这整个基地的供热系统都是在中心控制的
Now if we can reach those control,
we can turn up the heating.
如果我们能够得着那些控制, 我们就可以调高温度
But how can we get there?
Ice Warriors are patrolling those corridors.
但我们怎么到那里呢？这些走道里都有寒冰勇士在巡逻
Aye, Yes I know. The maintenance tunnel's over here!
是, 我知道．这里有维修通道！
(WHISPERS) All right, Fewsham, now!
好了, Fewsham, 动手！
I can't! They'll kill us both!
我不能！他们会把我们俩都杀了！
- You've got to help me!
- I can't, I daren't.
- 你必须帮我！  - 我不能, 我不敢！
Very well, I shall do it by myself.
好吧, 那我就自己干
If I am caught, which is most likely,
we will both get killed.
如果我被抓了, 这非常可能发生, 我们俩都会被杀
(RASPING WHISPER) Do not move!
不许动！
I was ordered to prepare the controls for transmission.
I’ve got to check that everything is in order.
我被要求准备传送控制, 我得检查一下所有东西是不是正常
(RASPING WHISPER) Return to where you were!
回到你原来的地方去！
(FEWSHAM) But this is most important!
但这事情很重要！
If you are trying to escape, I shall destroy you!
如果你是打算逃跑, 我会灭了你！
I'm not trying to escape!
我没打算逃跑！
Go back to where you were!
回到你原来的地方！
All right! All right!
好吧, 好吧！
Wait!
等一下！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Open it!
打开它！
I said, ''Open it''!
我说了, ＂打开它＂！
What are these things?
这些是什么东西？
They look like seed pods.
看起来像是种子荚
(CHOKING COUGH)
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
What's happened to him?
他怎么了？
Is he dead?
他死了吗？
We can get through it here then.
Turn the heating up, knock the Warriors out
我们可以从这里过去, 调高温度, 敲晕寒冰勇士
- We can rescue the Doctor.
- And T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
- 我们就可以救出博士 - 然后再用 T-Mat 传送回地球
- But I thought that T-Mat's broken down.
- Not any more, I repaired it.
- 但我记得 T-Mat 坏掉了  - 不再是了, 我修好了
Can we get this cover off?
你能把这个盖子拿掉吗？
This part of the base has been disused for ages.
It's rusted. It will take some time.
基地的这一片已经很久没有使用了, 都锈了, 要点时间
The Doctor may not have much time.
博士可能没有太多时间
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You will prepare to activate the cubicle
and transmit to London.
你准备好, 马上要激活格子间, 传送物品去伦敦
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING) Obey!
服从！
Activate!
激活！
(TRILLING HUM)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
Commander Radnor! T-Mat is working.
指挥官 Radnor！ T-Mat 正在工作
- Working? Kelly must have got through!
- Splendid!
- 工作！Kelly 肯定要过来了  - 太好了
What is it?
这是什么？
It's alive!
是活的！